The Galaxy awaits.
The Super Mario Galaxy Movie is a family, fantasy,
comedy film directed by Michael Jelenic.
A new movie based on the world of Super Mario Bros.
that further broadens Mario's world with a bright and fun story.
Mario (voice), played by Chris Pratt.
Princess Peach (voice), played by Anya Taylor-Joy.
Luigi (voice), played by Charlie Day.
Bowser (voice), played by Jack Black.
Bowser Jr. (voice), played by Benny Safdie.
Toad (voice), played by Keegan-Michael Key.
The Super Mario Galaxy Movie is an upcoming animated adventure comedy film based on the
2007 video game Super Mario Galaxy and Nintendo's broader Mario franchise.
The sequel to The Super Mario Bros.
Movie (2023), it is being directed by Aaron Horvath and
Michael Jelenic and written by Matthew Fogel.
Chris Pratt, Anya Taylor-Joy, Charlie Day, Jack Black, Keegan-Michael Key, and Kevin Michael
Richardson reprise their roles, while Benny Safdie and Brie Larson join the cast.
It is being produced by Illumination and Nintendo,
and distributed by Universal Pictures.
In the film, Mario and Luigi join Princess Peach and Toad on an adventure
into outer space to face off against Bowser's son, Bowser Jr.
Nintendo president Shuntaro Furukawa stated in May 2021 that Nintendo was interested in producing more
animated films based on its properties if the then-untitled Mario film was successful.
Illumination CEO and producer Chris Meledandri was asked about the
possibility of a sequel to The Super Mario Bros.
Movie before the film's release in April 2023.
Following its box office success, a new animated Mario film was announced to be in development at
Illumination in March 2024, with Horvath and Jelenic returning as directors and Fogel as screenwriter.
The Super Mario Galaxy Movie is scheduled to be theatrically
released in the United States on April 1, 2026.
The film explores themes of galaxy, sequel, based on video game, magic land.
The tone is lighthearted.